uh tonight we've got Ryan joining us
呃今晚我们有赖安加入我们
from proof proof point and he's the
从证明证明点，他是
senior vice president of cyber security
网络安全高级副总裁
strategy Ryan it's nice to have you here
策略瑞恩很高兴有你在这里
thanks for joining us tonight it's great
感谢今晚加入我们这很棒
to be here Ryan can you kind of tell us
在 这里瑞安你可以告诉我们
a little bit about proofpoint just out
有点关于证明点
the gate so that we so the viewers who
大门让我们这样的观众谁
are not familiar with your company can
不熟悉你的 公司可以
just kind of have a bit of a back story
只是有点背后的故事
as to what it is that you do yeah sure
至于你确实是这么做的
so we're a publicly-listed cyber
所以我们是一个公开上市的网络
security company we focus on protecting
我们专注于保护安全公司
the way people work which is absolutely
人们工作的方式绝对是这样
under assault these days mostly by
这些天大部分时间受到袭击
threats transmitted by email social
社交电子邮件传播的威胁
media and as we're going to talk about
媒体和我们将 要谈论的
tonight all the laps very good thanks
今晚所有的圈子非常好，谢谢
now you perform threat summaries and
现在你执行威胁摘要和
analyses over the course of any given
分析任何给定的过程
year and your quarter three summary just
一年和你的季度三总结
came out I believe just a couple of days
我相信只有几天
ago if i'm not mistaken so could you
以前如果我没有弄错你也可以
tell us a little bit about what you've
告诉我们一些关于你的东西
seen as far as the trends go in kind of
只要趋势是实物化就可以看到
the malware you know how things of
你知道这些恶意软件是怎么回事
transition I've seen a lot of transition
过渡我已经看到很多转变
over to mobile and that's a big concern
移动到手机，这是一个很大的关注
I'd love to hear a little bit about what
我很想 听到一 点点什么
you found in your current summary before
你之前在你当前的总结中找到了
we kind of really get into things
我们真的很喜欢事情
tonight yeah absolutely hey I mean we
今晚是绝对嘿我的意思是我们
see a very broad swath of data we see
看到我们看到的非常广泛的数据
the email traffic for about just north
电子邮件的流量只有 北部
fifty percent with Fortune 100 some of
百分之五十与财富100的一些
the largest organizations in the world
世界上最大的组织
and operating some of those sensitive
并操作其中一些敏感的
sectors so quite a lot of the Wolves
这些地区相当多的狼队
threats hit them in some way shape or
威胁击中了他们以某种方式或
form and as he looked at the threat
形式，并在他看着威胁
landscape in q3 it was basically a
在q3景观基本上是a
magnified version of what we saw in the
我们在英国看到的放大版本
three months prior to that you had
之前三个月， 你有
ransomware absolutely out of control on
勒索软件绝对失控
the email vector on it one particular
它的一个特别的电子邮件矢量
ransomware family in fact known as
勒索软件家族其实被称为
lackey for the file extension it creates
它创建的文件扩展名为
was responsible for about ninety seven
约九十七人负责
percent of the billions and billions of
数十亿和数十亿美元的百分比
malicious messages that we saw swims
我们看到游泳的恶意信息
three are we talking like an evolution
我们三人正在谈论进化
of say the cryptolocker style ransomware
说 cryptolocker风格勒索软件
here on PCs are we looking at as this
在PC上，我们正在看这个
evolved to to other platforms as well it
演变到其他平台 以及它
is mostly silky see specific the
大多是丝绸般的看具体的
cryptolocker crypt XX there are actually
cryptolocker crypt XX实际上有
dozens of families of ransom yeah
几十个赎金家庭是啊
it's actually up about fifty three
它实际上高达五十三
percent in the last quarter alone in
仅在上个季度的百分比
there all of course related in that they
当然，这些都与他们有关
try and do similar things they're
尝试做类似的事情
actually kind of more interesting
实际上更有趣
versions of rents where emerging that do
新兴的租金版本
slightly different things I would point
稍微不同的东西， 我会指出
out one of my personal I wouldn't say
我的个人之一我不会说
favorites but ones of interest that
最喜欢的，但有兴趣的
that's called petia PTY a that actually
实际上这就是所谓的佩蒂亚PTY
does what the malware in the Sony attack
做索尼攻击中的恶意软件
famously did really over rights the
着名的做了真正的权利
Master Boot Record of the computer
计算机的主引导记录
rendering it unusable at the time it's
使其在当时无法使用
it's actually rebooted so ransomware is
它实际上重新启动，所以勒索软件是
continuing to evolve not just on PCs but
不断发展，不仅仅是PC， 而是
it's been extending to other platforms
它一直在扩展到其他平台
as well there is ransomware that now
以及现在有勒索软件
exists in the wild for Android devices
存在于Android设备的野外
there were occasional flurries of Little
偶尔也会有Little的风潮
Mac flare-ups that didn't tend to be
那些并不倾向于的Mac突发事件
very common there was actually even a
甚至有一个很常见的
ransomware variant for linux that didn't
没有的Linux勒索软件变种
last very long before someone actually
实际上在某人之前很久
figured out what their key generation
想出了他们的关键一代
algorithm was oh very good way to
算法是非常好的方法
actually decrypt my files paint a
实际上解密我的文件绘制一个
Bitcoin ransom just for those viewers
只为 那些观众提供 比特币赎金
who are here tonight and not familiar
谁今晚在这里，不熟悉
with terms the terminology that we may
用我们可能的术语来表示术语
be using ransomware is is a fairly
使用勒索软件是相当的
frightening type of malware because it
因为它可怕的类型的恶意软件
can cause data loss data theft people
可能导致数据丢失数据被盗用
being able to compromise your files and
能够妥协你的文件和
that's where things get very scary
这是事情变得非常可怕的地方
because you may have pictures of your
因为你可能有你的照片
kids or you may have company emails you
孩子或你可能有公司的电子邮件给你
may have very important business data
可能有非常重要的商业数据
customer information and things like
客户信息和类似的东西
that and the reason that this type of
那和这种类型的原因
malware is called ransomware is
恶意软件被称为勒索软件
essentially it holds your files ransom
基本上它保存你的文件赎金
and then usually gives a prompt or
然后通常会给出提示或
something along those lines that says
沿着这些说法
hey you need to call this number you
嘿，你需要给你打这个号码
need to do this or that and transfer
需要做 这个或那个 并转移
money or provide a credit card
钱或提供信用卡
information there holding your files
信息那里拿着你的文件
ransom and that's a very scary thing so
赎金，这是 非常可怕的事情
we're starting to see this on the
我们开始看到这一点
Android platform you say we are and and
Android平台，你说我们是和
the the malware landscape for mobile
移动设备的恶意软件环境
devices is is one that's very much
设备是非常多的
emerging you see mobile malware
新兴的你会看到移动恶意软件
basically a few years behind the
基本上落后了几年
evolution of the same sorts of threats
同类威胁的演变
that affect pcs okay
那影响个人电脑没关系
but there of course extremely related in
但在那里当然非常相关
what they're trying to do and also how
他们想要做什么以及如何做
they represent themselves if you think
他们代表自己，如果你认为
about the typical ransomware that a
关于典型的勒索软件a
person would receive on a PC it's
人会在PC上收到它
probably actually going to arrive in an
可能实际上会到达一个
email it'll be attached as a file that
电子邮件将附加为一个文件
looks like a very legitimate business
看起来像一个非常合法的企业
document may be a financial statement or
文件可能是财务报表或
an invoice that has some urgency to it
一个有一些紧迫性的发票
right this is past due please open this
这是过期，请打开此
up and pay it something along those
并支付这些东西
lines the sort of thing that most of us
排成我们大多数人的那种东西
would absolutely open and and then it
将绝对开放，然后它
would of course if you clicked on the
当然如果你点击了
little yellow bar at the top actually
实际上顶部的小黄条
start encrypting your files on the
开始加密你的文件
mobile side it's a little different in
移动方面，它有点不同
that the ransomware has to exist in the
该勒索软件已在存在
form of an app that's really the only
这是真正唯一的应用程序形式
way that sort of thing can be installed
方式可以安装那种东西
on most mobile devices in the way that
在大多数移动设备上
these system architecture operating
这些系统架构在运行
system architecture effective works so
系统架构效果如此
what that means for the end user is
这对最终用户意味着什么
you're probably going to receive mobile
你可能会收到手机
amounts ransomware via a link again that
再次通过链接勒索勒索软件
could come to you by an email it
可以通过电子邮件找到你
actually could come via an SMS as well
实际上也可以通过短信来发送
and if you go to that link and install
如果你去那个链接并安装
an app most of the time it's not going
大多数情况下应用程序都不适用
to come from google play or rather
来自谷歌 播放或宁可
what's sanctioned app store that app can
该应用可以批准哪些应用商店
do whatever you entrust it to do on your
做你所托付的事情
device and most people when they install
设备和大多数人在安装时
something to tap ok ok ok I want to use
点击确定好吧好吧我想使用
this app and that's very much how
这个应用程序，这是非常多的
reservoir tends to evolve on the mobile
水库倾向于在移动设备上发展
platforms can I throw a scenario at you
平台可以向你抛出一个场景
Ryan that my wife actually encountered
瑞安，我的妻子实际遇到
just this past week just just because
就在这个过去的一周，只是因为
what we've seen on PCs and now we are
我们在PC上看到的， 现在我们都是
starting to see on on mobile as well and
也开始在手机上看到
you've likely seen it a lot longer time
你可能会看到更长的时间
than I have because of the industry that
比我因为那个行业而拥有
you're in my wife was apparently this is
你在我的 妻子显然是这样的
the story anyway so you can tell me if
无论如何，所以你可以 告诉我如何
she this is this is the lie detector
她这是这个测谎器
test here so she was looking at news
在这里测试，所以她正在看新闻
sites and reading blogs and things like
网站和阅读博客和类似的东西
that and all of a sudden her phone this
那一下子她的电话就这样了
is an android device said your phone is
是一款Android设备，表示您的手机是
infected now that Tim he strikes me as
现在感染了Tim，他让我感觉像
possibly infected advertising but what
可能感染了广告，但是什么
was different about this is she quickly
与此不同的是她很快
exited out because she she knows too you
退出，因为她也知道你
know
知道
get out of anything that looks like it
摆脱任何 看起来像它 的东西
might be suspicious but then handed her
可能会怀疑， 但随后递给她
phone to me in order to just make sure
电话给我， 以便只要确保
that everything's okay and sure enough
一切都很好，果然
on her dashboard was a root tool for
在她的仪表板上是一个根本工具
rooting the phone and something that is
生根电话，东西是
commonly used by hackers as well as
通常由黑客使用以及
legitimate users to root a phone so that
合法用户根源电话
they have full access to the root
他们可以完全访问根目录
filesystem so how is it that something
文件系统， 那它 怎么 样
like that could get into her phone just
就像那样可能会让她进入她的手机
surfing the web so that is it I think
网上冲浪，这是 我认为
your instincts were correct there that
你的直觉在那里是正确的
is what we would call mal vertising
就是我们所说的马尔科夫垂直
right so a fully legitimate site that
这是一个完全合法的网站
engages with a third-party provider for
与第三方供应商合作
to fill the advertising space on that
以填补该广告空间
site which is equally true in a
网站同样如此
traditional web browser on a PC and in a
PC上和 传统网络上的传统网络浏览器
mobile web browser on a mobile device
移动设备上的移动网络浏览器
that they will serve up ads that very
他们会投放广告
often are malicious and point to things
往往是恶意的，指向的东西
that either automatically invoke a
要么自动调用一个
download or invoke a download in such a
下载或调用这样的下载
way that then the screen is immediately
那么屏幕立即就是这样
obscured there's actually a strange sort
模糊了，实际上是一种奇怪的类型
of cousin to this which even exists on
表兄弟对此甚至存在
iOS which we often refer to as scareware
我们经常称之为恐慌软件的 iOS
where if you browse to the wrong site
如果你浏览到错误的网站
and you can get there any number of ways
你可以通过很多方式到达那里
including by an advertising link for the
包括通过广告链接
sole legitimate site right if your
唯一的合法网站，如果你的权利
browser the wrong site it fills the
浏览器填写错误的网站
screen and it basically enters into what
屏幕，它基本上进入了什么
is it was effectively and anyone has
这是有效的，任何人都有
ever taken a computer science course
曾参加计算机科学课程
will know about this mistake what's
会知道 这个错误是什么
called an infinite loop right so if you
所谓的无限循环， 所以如果你
write a software program usually
通常编写一个软件程序
incorrectly it will essentially go
不正确的，它将基本上去
around in circles if you make a certain
如果你确定的话，可以绕圈子
type of coding sting in this case the
在这种情况下编码的类型是
attackers are actually intentionally
攻击者实际上是故意的
making that mistake so that the phone
犯这样的错误，让电话
effectively goes around in circles while
同时有效地绕圈
the web browser is running what is
网页浏览器正在运行什么
actually JavaScript code to those who
实际上JavaScript代码给那些谁
are technically interested right it will
技术上感兴趣的权利
then basically freeze the screen display
然后基本冻结屏幕显示
a message usually fairly threatening
一条消息通常相当具有威胁性
message like the one I'm sure your wife
像我相信你的妻子的消息
saw yeah and i will tell you to either
看到了，我会告诉你
call a number or visit a website and pay
拨打电话号码或访问网站并付款
some Bitcoin to unlock the phone but
一些比特币来解锁手机，但是
what it really is is just a broken piece
它究竟是什么只是一块碎片
of JavaScript on a website Wow and for
在网站上的JavaScript和哇
users perspective the phone becomes
用户对电话的看法变成了
unusable
不可用
because all the classic techniques don't
因为所有的经典技术都没有
work you can't tap it and i cant it wont
工作你不能点击它，我不能
do anything more technically
在技​​术上做更多的事情
sophisticated users will probably
老练的用户可能会
immediately be thinking but why don't
立即想到，但为什么不
you do a hard reset that's actually the
你做了一个硬重置，这实际上是
answer you push those buttons on the
回答你按下这些按钮
phone for iOS and different combinations
手机为iOS和不同的组合
for Android and just reset the phone
为Android和刚刚重置手机
everything will be fine right absolutely
一切都会很好
we saw fraudsters making quite a lot of
我们看到了骗子做了相当多的
money this is scam is it on iOS device
这是钱在iOS设备上是骗局
so is it quite often strictly a trick is
所以它通常严格来说就是一个诀窍
it a social engineering trick to try to
这是一种社交工程技巧
get you to follow the directions or is
让你按照指示或是
it actually infected the system most of
它实际上大部分感染了系统
the time it is a trick and that follows
这是一个技巧，随之而来的时间
a general pattern in cyber ground there
在那里的网络基地的一般模式
is a huge shift towards social
是 对社会 的巨大 转变
engineering away from sophisticated
工程远离复杂
technical exploits this doesn't always
技术漏洞并非总是如此
get accurately captured in the media
在媒体中准确捕捉
where there is still quite a lot of
哪里还有很多
focus on things like I would call out
专注于我会说出的事情
the Pegasus attack from a couple months
飞马座几个月的袭击
ago when I was a state-sponsored attack
之前 我是一个国家发起的攻击
on a couple of journalists that actually
实际上在一些记者身上
involved three different iOS zero days
涉及三个不同的iOS零日
chained together that's not the likely
链接在一起，这不是可能的
thing everyone is going to encounter
每个人都会遇到的事情
right it is much more likely to run into
正确的是，它很可能 会遇到
this sort of scare where it's designed
这种恐怖的设计
to get a little money out of you hmm
从你那里得到一点钱嗯
okay so why would you say this type of
好吧，那么为什么你会说这种类型的
attack is on the rise you alluded to the
袭击正在上升，你提到了
fact that some of these malware creators
事实上，这些恶意软件的创造者
are making money off of this off of
正在从这个关闭中赚钱
tricking users obviously that's the case
很明显，欺骗用户就是这种情况
what what is the driving force behind
背后的动力是什么？
behind malware rising on the mobile
背后的恶意软件上升
platform it's simple economics I think
平台， 我认为 这很简单
at this point now where authors are
现在是作者所在的时间点
basically businessman in most ways and
基本上是商人在大多数方面和
their businesses look like SAS
他们的业务看起来像SAS
businesses they want us there are
他们想要我们的企业有
resources where the greatest return is
最大回报的资源
and as people move away from traditional
随着人们摆脱传统
computing platforms like pcs and onto
计算平台，如个人电脑和上
mobile devices more sensitive data goes
移动设备更敏感的数据
there to people care more about the
那里给人们更多的关心
information that's stored there than
一个储存 有比信息
they might care about the information on
他们可能会关心这些信息
their own pc so it's a very logical
他们自己的电脑，所以这是非常合乎逻辑的
place for the malware authors to try and
让恶意软件作者尝试使用
move to even though actually most mobile
即使实际上是最流动的
operating systems and are included are a
操作系统和包含的都是a
lot more secure than most historical PC
比大多数历史PC更安全
operating systems
操作系统
because they were constructed at a later
因为它们是在稍后建造的
date when more things were known about
约会了解更多事情的日期
what good security practice looked like
什么样的安全实践看起来像
an operating system so when it comes to
一个操作系统，所以当它涉及到
these you know increased attacks is
这些你知道增加的攻击是
there a specific group that's being
有一个特定的组
targeted like is it are they primarily
有针对性就像它是主要的
trying to hit like elderly people who
试图打击像老人一样
are just getting onto these phones out
正在把这些电话拿出来
no clue what they're doing or is is
不知道他们在做什么或是在做什么
there a target group that are they're
有一个目标群体， 他们是
looking to get are just a blank and see
希望得到只是一个空白，看看
who's out there I mobile malware at this
谁在那里我在这个移动恶意软件
point is very difficult to target so it
点是非常困难的目标，所以它
is sort of spray and pray from the
是有点喷雾，并从中祈祷
attackers perspectives they're looking
攻击者的视角他们正在寻找
to put malicious links in very cheap
以非常便宜的方式放置恶意链接
ways on lots of sites where they're
他们在很多网站上的方式
likely to encounter the sort of
可能会遇到那种
unsophisticated users you're talking
不熟练的用户你说话
about on the PC side of things
关于事物的PC端
ransomware 4pcs is often highly targeted
勒索软件4个通常是高度针对性的
at organizations that are going to have
在那些将会有的组织中
sort of things like file shares which we
像我们这样的文件共享
saw aliens like crypt XX go after those
看到外星人像地穴XX去追赶那些
are the shared servers where a lot of
是很多共享服务器
different people put their files that
不同的人把 他们的文件
are tend to be very valuable to say a
倾向于说非常有价值
hospital or a school district or or
医院或学区或or
incorporation and that type of malware
合并和该类型的恶意软件
is very very targeted at a different
是非常非常针对不同的
organization it's likely to have a lot
它可能会有很多组织
of money because they care up or a lot
的钱，因为他们关心或很多
of money that they'll pay to unlock
他们将花钱解锁的钱
those files because they care a lot
这些文件，因为他们关心很多
about the value of those files on the
关于这些文件上的价值
mobile side is much harder to do that
移动端更难做到这一点
same sort of targeting that is fairly
同样的定位 是相当的
easily do based on something like email
很容易做基于像电子邮件的东西
address sure I would expect that the pc
地址肯定我会期望的电脑
and the things based on what you're
和基于你的东西
saying there would be probably grander
说可能会更宏伟
scale as well because if I were to you
规模也是如此，因为如果我是你
know as a if I was a hacker attacking a
知道如果我是一个黑客攻击一个
company if I could get into one system
公司如果我可以进入 一个系统
that could go out on the network and
这可能会在网络上发生
encrypt all of the files on network
加密网络上的所有文件
shares usually there's a you know a
股票通常有你知道的一个
shared server somewhere that's got a
共享服务器的某个地方有一个
samba share that you know the whole
桑巴分享，你知道整个
company uses then all of a sudden you're
公司使用，然后突然你是
not in trouble right and you yet
没有麻烦， 对你还没有
actually have now seen ransomware go
实际上现在已经看到勒索软件了
after that first so it won't encrypt the
之后，首先，所以它不会加密
logo right look for that network share
徽标右键查找该网络共享
first yeah and very often it might even
首先是， 而且很多时候甚至可能
look for the backups to that network
寻找该网络的备份
share first before it starts to actually
在实际开始之前先分享
encrypting the primary which is
加密主要的是
extremely clever and extremely evil when
非常聪明和极其邪恶的时候
you think about it yeah it's funny
你想想看， 这很有趣
though you mentioned you know trying to
尽管你提到你知道尝试
go after things like me
追求像我这样的事情
the education settings and immediately
教育环境和立即
my thought goes to the fact that you
我的想法是关于你的事实
know with my kids school they don't send
知道我的孩子学校他们 不发送
home or they're trying to move away from
家或他们试图离开
sending home paper paper knowns and it's
发送家庭纸张纸知道 ， 这是
kids or have computers with emails and
孩子或有电脑和电子邮件
they're emailing parents and I'm
他们正在给父母发电子邮件，而我是
thinking man if they can infect a school
思想的人，如果他们能感染一所学校
and then hit all the parents you know by
然后打你认识的所有父母
cycling through an email I mean you can
通过电子邮件骑车我的意思是你可以
do some serious damage when they had a
当他们有一个时会造成严重的伤害
absolutely have it made it if you think
如果你认为它绝对有它
about how much you would personally pay
关于你会亲自支付多少钱
for the files that are either on your
对于是否在你的文件
mobile device or on your PC if they were
移动设备或在您的PC上，如果他们
locked up by somebody and you didn't
被某人锁起来而你没有
have them somewhere else it's usually a
有他们在别的地方通常是
big number and that's why the rent
大数字， 这就是为什么租金
ransomware actually is a is a reasonably
勒索软件实际上是一个合理的
quantifiable security problem which
量化的安全问题
actually sits in contrast to a lot of
实际上与许多相反
others and it's because of one of the
别人，这是因为其中之一
fundamental pieces of technology that's
基本的技术是这样的
enabled this to grow and scale which is
使这成长和规模是这样的
Bitcoin right so we know what bitcoin
比特币是正确的，所以我们知道比特币
wallets are associated with these
钱包与这些相关联
ransomware campaign attackers and we can
勒索软件攻击者和我们可以
look because it's public ledger like how
看起来是因为它像公共账本一样
much money they're making off of all
他们所赚的钱很多
this and it's hundreds millions of
这是数以百万计的
dollars so we're talking about anonymous
美元，所以我们在谈论匿名
currency here being used in an
货币在这里被用于
untrackable way to put things into
不可思议的方式把事情放进去
perspective because you think you know
因为你认为你知道
well I wouldn't pay for my files and
以及我不会支付我的文件和
things but let's say you know look at
事情，但让我们说你知道看看
your phone pull out your phone and take
你的手机拿出 你的手机并拿走
a look now here we are in 2016 my phone
现在 看看 我们在2016年我的手机
is chock full of photos of my kids that
充满了我的孩子们的照片
mean a lot people take their phones to
意味着很多人把手机带到了
weddings and special events they take a
婚礼和特殊活动
bunch of pictures and they're not always
一堆照片，他们并不总是
prompt to back up those files and
提示备份这些文件和
transfer them which means having at
转让他们意味着有
least two copies and one copy that is
至少有两个副本和一个副本
completely air-gapped from the network
与网络完全无缝连接
so we're talking an external hard drive
所以我们正在谈论一个外部硬盘 驱动器
stored in a drawer somewhere or
存放在某个地方或抽屉里
something like that but to put it into
类似的东西，但把 它放进去
perspective here so if I had a hard
这里的角度，所以如果我有一个艰难的
drive with all of my data on it that was
用我所有的数据的驱动就可以了，这 是
really important to me and this happens
对我来说真的很重要， 而且 会发生
okay so here's a scenario you've got a
好吧，所以这里有一个你有一个场景
hard drive that has all of the files
包含所有文件的硬盘驱动器
that are your kids photos and all of
这是你的孩子的照片和所有
these other things that mean a lot to
这些其他事情意味着很多
you to look at it from a consumer
你从消费者那里看它
standpoint because your phone is
因为你的手机是立体的
generally your
一般你的
files and that hard drive crashes will I
文件和硬盘驱动器崩溃将我
go to data recovery and say okay I need
去数据恢复和说好吧我需要
these files these are important to me
这些文件对我来说很重要
how much is it going to cost to get
要花多少钱才能获得
these files back and this is a
这些文件回来了，这是一个
legitimate my hard drive has crashed I
我的硬盘驱动器崩溃了
need these files back and sometimes a
需要返回这些文件，有时需要a
data recovery can cost thousands of
数据恢复可能会花费数千美元
dollars in a worst-case scenario so when
美元在最坏的情况下，所以什么时候
someone takes over my phone and says for
有人接管我的电话，并说
300 pounds or you know six hundred
300磅或你知道六百
dollars you're going to get your files
美元你将得到你的文件
back the temptation may be there to say
回到诱惑可能在那里说
okay yeah I'm going to do that because
好吧，我会这样做，因为
these are important to me it's my data
这些对我来说很重要， 这是我的数据
recovery it's the way to get these files
恢复它是获取这些文件的方式
back right how dangerous is it for us
背对我们有多危险
Ryan to actually pursue that and hit
瑞恩实际上追求和击中
that button that says okay I'm going to
那个按钮说，好吧，我要去
I'm going to buy my files back I think
我想买回我的文件
there are really two concerns that pop
真的有 两个问题，流行
up there and the first one I would
在那里和第一个我会
actually say is an ethics concern the
其实说的是道德问题
people behind cybercrime are very bad
网络犯罪背后的人非常糟糕
people cyber crime has been used to fund
人们的网络犯罪已被用于资助
real world terrorism as well as cyber
真实的世界恐怖主义以及网络
terrorism and giving money to bad people
恐怖主义和捐钱给坏人
is not something anyone should do
不是任何人应该做的
lightly so what's best is of course to
轻微如此，最好的当然 是
have that air-gapped copy of all of the
有所有的空隙的副本
data that you cared about that doesn't
你关心的数据不会
actually run the risk of being encrypted
实际上存在被加密的风险
by ransomware but the second concern is
通过勒索软件，但第二个问题是
is one of simple logistics very often
是很简单的物流之一
these read somewhere these ransomware
这些阅读这些勒索软件的地方
variants will have a very short fuse and
变种将有一个非常短的保险丝和
they will count down and they were awful
他们会倒数， 他们是可怕的
they will often destroy your files along
他们经常会破坏你的文件
the way as they count down often times
的方式，因为他们倒计时很多时候
you don't have more than 24 hours so one
你没有超过24小时，所以一个
of one of the really i find this almost
其中一个真的我几乎找到了
a disturbing practice but it's sort of
一个令人不安的做法，但它是有点
the reality we live in one of the
我们住在其中一个的现实
practices that's starting to happen at
这些行为已经开始发生
large companies is they will actually go
大公司是他们真的会去的
out and buy some Bitcoin in advance
提前购买一些比特币
because it's not the sort of thing that
因为它不是那种东西
you can go get from the bank down the
你可以从银行下来
street yeah just in case they need it
街头是啊，以防万一他们 需要它
for ransom worst arrows because this has
对于赎金最差的箭头，因为这已经
become absolutely endemic why they
为什么会变得绝对流行？
wouldn't be sending billions of emails
不会发送数十亿封电子邮件
is it if it didn't work
是否它不起作用？
because they they have to pay some
因为他们必须付出一些
botnet operator you know that's a that
僵尸网络运营商，你知道这是一个
is a sad fact I'd be sure we're speaking
是 一个令人伤心的事实，我敢肯定我们在说话
with ryan callum burr from proof point
与ryan callum毛刺从证明点
and he is the senior vice president of
而他的高级副总裁
cybersecurity strategy there at proof
网络安全策略证明
point com we need to ask it and I hate
点com我们需要问它，我讨厌
to do this kind of a question but
做这样一个 问题，但是
Android versus iOS we're talking about
我们正在讨论Android和iOS
mobile tonight where are we safest
今晚移动我们最安全的地方
between these two platforms if you are
如果你是这两个平台之间的话
talking about the average user your
谈论你的普通用户
safest on iOS I simply because that's
我最简单的就是因为这一点
all the time that we have for tonight so
我们 今晚所有的时间都 如此
not what I wanted to hear yeah I know
不是我想听到的是我知道的
that the if you look at the basic facts
如果你看看基本的事实
that go into evaluating the threats that
进入评估这些威胁
you will very likely encounter on an
你很可能会遇到一个
Android device versus an iOS device you
Android设备与iOS设备相比
really have no more than three major
真的没有超过三个主要
considerations one is how easy it is to
考虑因素之一是它是多么容易
update the pad update and patch that
更新垫更新并修补它
device as vulnerabilities are exposed
设备作为漏洞暴露
and here this is not actually androids
而这里这其实并不是机器人
fault it's not anything that Google can
这不是Google所能做到的
control but when you are on the carrier
控制，但当你在 载体上
variants of Android and right don't get
Android的变体和权利没有得到
updates the same way you do for iOS
更新方式与iOS相同
which is much more controllable in that
这是可控的
sense your windows of exposure for these
感受你的这些暴露窗口
broad-based types of attacks like stage
基础广泛的攻击类型如舞台
fright most notably are longer and that
惊人的最明显的是更长和那
is something that impacts the average
是影响平均水平的东西
user especially when some of those those
特别是那些用户中的某些用户
attacks can be spread by simple SMS and
攻击可以通过简单的SMS传播
not anything that can be controlled the
不是任何可以 控制的东西
lighting user right the second piece of
照亮用户权利的第二块
mobile risk that I think is relevant
移动风险， 我认为是相关的
here is the apps themselves it is very
这是应用程序本身，它是非常
very difficult although possible to find
尽管可能找到很困难
your way to a rogue App Store for iOS it
你的方式到iOS的流氓App Store它
actually in most cases involves doing
实际上在大多数情况下涉及到做
one of two things either jailbreaking
其中之一是越狱
the device which is complicated and most
该设备是最复杂和最复杂的设备
users don't even have the technical
用户甚至没有技术
sophistication to do
要做的复杂
I wouldn't recommend it unless you are
我不会推荐它，除非你是
an expert you're very attuned to the
你非常熟悉的专家
security settings link uncomfortable
安全设置链接不舒服
with or actually the second way that you
与或实际上 你 的第二种方式
can often get an app that has not gone
往往可以得到一个没有消失的应用程序
through any security review onto your
通过任何安全审查到您的
device is to find your way to any one of
设备是找到你的方式任何一个
the many many rogue app stores out there
那里有许多流氓应用程序商店
we monitor about 150 of them actually
我们实际监测了其中约150个
that they do something that's kind of
他们做的东西是一种
interesting so if you are a company say
有趣的是，如果你是一个公司说
I'm acne inked and I have an acne app
我痤疮墨水，我有一个痤疮应用程序
for my own employees but I don't want to
为我自己的员工， 但我不想
put this in the public App Store I can
把它放在公共的 App Store里我可以
go out to apple and pay a few hundred
出去吃苹果，付几百块钱
dollars i believe this for what's called
美元我相信这是所谓的
an enterprise signing certificate and
企业签字证书和
then i can write my own apps using xcode
那么我可以使用xcode编写自己的应用程序
the same way you develop normal iOS apps
与开发普通iOS应用程序的方式相同
I can sign them using my own certificate
我可以使用我自己的证书签署他们
and then I can provision them using
然后我可以使用它们
what's called an enterprise app store so
这就是所谓的企业应用程序商店
this Acme app gets on to all my users
这Acme应用程序得到我所有的用户
devices and it never gets to the public
设备，它永远不会公开
app store that actually has a lot of
应用商店，实际上有很多
legitimate business purposes that you
合法的商业目的，你
can imagine sure does not but cyber
可以想象，肯定不会但网络
criminals have realized that oh wait
罪犯已经意识到，哦，等待
what if I steal one of those enterprise
如果我偷走了那些企业中的一员，该怎么办？
signing apps and then come up with
签署应用程序，然后想出来
counterfeit versions of all those very
所有这些非法的假冒版本
popular apps that everybody likes to pay
每个人都喜欢支付的流行应用程序
a lot of money for I could set up one
很多钱我可以成立一个
amazing counterfeit app store basically
惊人的假冒应用商店基本上
add Napster for apps for iOS because
为iOS应用添加Napster，因为
there's actually no technical limit how
实际上没有技术限制
many apps you can sign with one error
许多应用程序可以用一个错误签名
price-cutting search ouch so now we are
降价搜索哎，现在我们是
actually seeing you saw this actually
实际上看到你真的看到了这个
for the first time at a very large
第一次是非常大的
healthcare company one of their users
健康公司是他们的用户之一
had interesting app on his or her phone
他或她的手机上有一个有趣的应用程序
I don't want to give anyone's identity
我不想给任何人的身份
whether yes actually it was a lego star
无论是实际上它是一个乐高星
wars out can that's not unusual at all
战争爆发可能并不罕见
yeah I have that on my phone for the
是的，我的手机上有这个
kids exactly but this lego star wars app
孩子们，但这个乐高星球大战的应用程序
didn't exist in any app store and it was
在任何应用程序商店都不存在， 它是
on an iOS device that wasn't jailbroken
在没有越狱的iOS设备上
so the question was where did it come
所以问题是它来自哪里
from and we eventually traced it back to
从我们最终追溯到
a very large counterfeit app store in
一家非常大的假冒应用商店
China called V share still running if
中国称V股仍在运行
you want to go check it out of each
你想去 检查每一个
Eircom where they can find
Eircom他们可以找到的地方
free versions of every popular paid app
每个流行付费应用的免费版本
in both the Google Play and Apple app
在Google Play和Apple 应用中
stores and they're just absolutely
商店，他们 只是绝对
identical except the fact that there's
除了有这个事实以外，完全相同
probably not wearing a good percentage
可能没有穿好比例
of them so that whole recommendation
他们这样整个推荐
just there we will retract that don't go
就在那里我们会收回那些不会去的
there don't install them that's like I
不要安装它们， 就像我一样
would just kind of qualify it and that
将 只是一种限定它和
the same thing is a maple pull on the
同样的事情是一个枫树拉
google site as well it's actually easier
谷歌网站以及它实际上更容易
to trust a another app store in the the
信任另一个应用商店
way the android operating system is is
Android操作系统的方式是
set up if you go to settings you can
如果你可以设置你的设置
actually trust absolute right turn on
实际上相信绝对的右转
like developer mode precisely and you're
像开发人员模式一样，你就是
in your and it you're not even actually
在你和它，你甚至不是真的
having to find your way to one of these
必须找到你的方式之一
crazy off friend app stores that are
疯狂的朋友应用程序商店是
actually very good at things like SEO so
其实很擅长 像SEO这样的事情
a google search for the free lego star
谷歌搜索免费的乐高明星
wars that will likely guide you there
可能会 引导你到那里的战争
but are not the sort of thing that the
但不是这种东西 的
normal user who stays within the bounds
保持在界限内的正常用户
of the app store is ever going to
的应用程序商店是永远不会
encounter and the interesting thing
相遇和有趣的事情
about those apps is because they've
关于这些应用程序是因为他们已经
never been reviewed by Apple or Google
从未经Apple或Google审核过
they could be doing anything on the
他们可以做 的 事情
device they gave me a full-blown remote
设备，他们给了我一个完整的遥控器
access virgin because it they can access
访问处女，因为他们可以访问
any private api and they've never gone
任何私人API，他们从来没有去过
through the traditional sorts of
通过传统的种类
security checks so actually the average
安全检查实际上是平均水平
user who stays within the bounds of a
保持在一个范围内的用户
typical app store will be fine on either
典型的应用程序商店将罚款
platform but lots of users really don't
平台，但很多用户确实没有
want to pay a few dollars for a nap and
想要支付几美元打个盹儿
find their way into a lot of trouble
找到自己的方式陷入了很多麻烦
probably you know and not to bring up
可能你知道，不要提出
old news here Ryan but we see it's not
这里有个新闻Ryan，但我们看到它不是
just for software piracy to get a free
只为软件盗版而获得免费
app we saw with that Pokemon go came
我们看到那个神奇宝贝去的应用程序
over and it wasn't available all around
结束了，它不是全部可用
the world so people were hearing about
这个世界让人们听到了
it the news was talking about it but
这个消息是在谈论它，但是
people couldn't install it so here in
人们无法在这里安装它
Canada for example people started going
例如加拿大人开始走了
to these counterfeit app stores and
到这些假冒应用商店和
installing it on their phone and that's
将它安装在手机上，就是这样
a good scenario you know a good example
一个很好的场景你就是一个很好的例子
of hey it's it's more than just piracy
嘿，这不仅仅是盗版
absolutely and we found one of the one
绝对和我们找到了一个
Pokemon go variant that had something
口袋妖怪去了变种，有东西
called a droid jack which is basically
称为基本上是一个机器人杰克
surveillance software
监视软件
in the codes for the Pokemon go app so
在口袋妖怪 去应用程序的代码如此
it's like super spy stuff here is yeah
这就像超级间谍的东西是耶
like that's like if you ever watch
就好像你曾经看过一样
person of interest and they the you know
感兴趣的人，他们是你知道的
blue gap or whatever the phones and
蓝色的差距或任何手机和
stuff and start the intercepting calls
东西，并开始拦截调用
and right so with those kind of apps
对于那些应用来说也是如此
like I know when the compromise Pokemon
就像我知道何时妥协口袋妖怪一样
goal apps are coming out i mean you
目标应用程序出来我的意思是你
download the one from the App Store and
从App Store下载一个
there's you know let's access your
你知道让我们访问你的
photos your camera that's the other
照相机，这是另一个
thing to your phone but then you get the
给你的手机的东西，但然后你得到的
malicious one and it wants to access
恶意的，它想访问
everything so if you get an app that you
一切如此，如果你得到一个应用程序，你
download and you notice it wants to
下载，你会注意到它想要的
access everything is that a good tip-off
访问一切都是一个很好的提示
that there's probably something wrong
有可能是错误的
with the app or is that just possible
与应用程序或只是可能的
that the programmers didn't really think
程序员没有真正想到
too much and we're like oh we need
太多了， 我们就像我们 需要的
access to everything just in case like
访问一切，以防万一
it is that a good indicator that there's
这是一个很好的指标
something wrong with the app it is a
它 是一个 错误的应用程序
good indicator that there is either
好的指标，也有
something wrong with the app or that the
应用程序出现问题或出现问题
developers don't pay enough attention to
开发人员不够重视
set the security and privacy concerns
设置安全 和隐私问题
right so it is something always to be
右所以它是 值得永远是
cognizant of that you are mostly going
认识到你主要是去
to be the one who subjects yourself to
成为自己的一员
security risk on a mobile platform
移动平台上的安全风险
simply because is they're very very
只是因为他们非常非常
secure operating systems by default both
安全操作系统默认都是
Android and iOS the apps though very
Android和iOS 的应用程序虽然非常
often have legitimate reasons to access
通常有正当理由进入
your data and Android and iOS don't
你的数据以及Android和iOS都没有
control what those apps do with your
控制这些应用程序对你的操作
data so if you are actually trusting
数据，所以如果你真的信任
that app and that app developer to
该应用程序和该应用程序开发人员
access some data on your device like
访问设备上的一些数据
your photos like your location like your
你的照片就像你的位置一样
emails like your SMS lawns you should
电子邮件像你的短信草坪你应该
think very hard about whether to accept
非常认真地考虑是否接受
that or not and just tapping through and
或不， 只是通过和
accepting the default settings is very
接受默认设置是非常的
often not a good idea but certainly for
往往不是一个好主意，但肯定是
me user perspectives were all fairly
我的用户观点都很公平
impatient now and it's not sort of thing
现在不耐烦，这不是什么问题
enough users pay attention to right so
足够的用户注意到这一点
that begs the question if you're you
如果你是你，那么就会产生问题
know you've done your whatever it is
知道你已经完成了 你的任何事情
you're doing you've installed this app
你正在做你已经安装了这个应用程序
is it just enough to delete
这仅仅是删除
you have to get rid of it like how do
你必须像怎样做才能摆脱它
you rid yourself to make sure that
你摆脱自己以确保这一点
you're protected and with that what
你受到保护，并与那个
happens if you've done a backup like say
如果你已经完成了像说的那样的备份，就会发生
you do have one of those malicious apps
你确实有这些恶意应用程序之一
on an iOS device where when you do your
在iOS设备上，当你做你的
backup that backup is everything if you
备份备份就是一切，如果你
do a restore you get everything unlike
做一个恢复你得到的一切不像
with an Android you can do your backup
用Android你可以做你的备份
of your photos so you have to wipe your
你的照片，所以你必须擦你的
phone you get through your photos back
电话你通过 你的照片回来
on much easier so right how do you get
很容易，所以你如何得到
rid of it and when it comes to backups
摆脱它，当涉及到备份
from your computer could they still be
从你的电脑，他们仍然可以
infected and are you just perpetually
感染，你只是永远
going in circles it is a good question
这是一个很好的问题
actually so one of the one of the
其实的一个，这样一个
examples that leaps to mind is I was
突然想到的例子是我
recently working with the chief
最近与首席合作
information security officer of the navy
海军信息安全官员
league like University on the East Coast
像东海岸的 大学一样
the United States and he had an
美国和他有一个
interesting problem with a professor the
与教授有趣的问题
professor just had somebody who was very
教授只是有一个非常的人
clearly reading his email and
明确阅读他的电子邮件和
downloading his files from a cloud file
从云文件下载他的文件
repository and that first wasn't being
知识库，那首先不是
terribly subtle about it and it didn't
它非常微妙，但事实并非如此
matter how many times the professor
事关教授多少次
changed his password this will still
这仍然会改变他的密码
happen so the the security officers are
发生，所以安全官员
quite rightly assumed that oh this is
很正确地认为，这是
probably a keylogger on your laptop
可能是笔记本上的键盘记录器
you've got some sort of malware there
那里有一些恶意软件
she brought in the laptop which was a
她带来了一 台笔记本电脑
normal windows pc scanned it with every
正常的Windows PC扫描每一个
tool he hat and it came back completely
工具他帽子，它完全回来了
clean so scrambling a bit he then asked
干净的这么争吵了一下，然后问道
the professor do you have any a home pc
教授你有没有家用电脑？
that you that you use I said no
你说你用我说不
absolutely not this is my only pc it's a
绝对不是这是我唯一的电脑它是
laptop and then thinking quickly the
笔记本电脑，然后迅速思考
follow-up question was all right is
后续的问题是所有正确的是
there any other device where you enter
还有其他设备在哪里输入
your password the professor has said
教授说过的密码
sharp i have iphone and so the security
尖锐我有iPhone和所以安全
officer looks at the iphone completely
官员完全看着iphone
normal up-to-date not jailbroken no
正常的最新不越狱
obvious signs of risk but it had about
有明显的风险迹象，但它有
200 apps on it so he asked him to take
200个应用程序， 所以他 让他拿
that the little view svt lightning cable
那个小小的视图就是闪电电缆
plug it back in to iTunes back up the
将其重新插回iTunes备份
phone and then resync and uncheck the
电话，然后重新同步并取消选中
one
一
box next to apps which is something you
框旁边的应用程序，这是你的东西
can actually do so they sink to
实际上可以这样做，他们沉入
everything except the apps and then
除应用程序之外的所有内容
change his password and that worked so
改变他的密码，这样工作
one of those apps was just stealing his
其中一个应用程序正在窃取他的
credentials over and over again and
一遍又一遍的信任和
that's the sort of thing we are seeing
这就是我们所看到的那种事情
happen more and more frequently as you
和你一样越来越频繁地发生
trust apps with even email credentials
使用电子邮件凭据信任应用
so like a third party email client for
所以就像第三方电子邮件客户端
example would be detective that can
例如可以 是侦探
trust with this and and that's actually
相信这一点，而那实际上是
compromising good in a much broader way
以更广泛的方式妥协
just even what's a mobile device scary
即使什么是移动设备可怕
stuff well you I appreciate your time so
好东西，我感谢你的 时间
much Ryan I know we've been speaking for
我知道我们一直在为之讲话
a little while about mobile malware and
一段时间关于移动恶意软件和
how that is impacting society and users
这是如何影响社会和用户的
in general we all have a phone in our
一般来说，我们都有在我们的电话
pocket the kind of the the final
囊中最后的那种
discussion that we need to have with you
讨论中，我们需要有一个 与你
is what is there you know on my computer
你在我的电脑上知道什么？
I've got anti-malware and I'm able to
我有反恶意软件，我可以
protect myself from computer viruses
保护自己免受电脑病毒侵害
with with anti malware on your phone is
与您的手机上的反恶意软件是
it as simple as installing an
就像安装一个一样简单
application that will protect you from
应用程序，将保护你免受
these kinds of things on both platforms
这两种平台上的这些东西
android and iOS it's not quite that
Android和iOS并不是那样
simple unfortunately because there's
不幸的是，因为有
really actually two things that you
真的有两件事是你的
would worry about one is these sort of
会担心这种情况
rogue apps that we've been talking about
我们一直在谈论流氓应用程序
which are often hard to identify and
这通常很难识别和
many of them actually make it into the
他们中的许多人实际上都把它变成了
proper app stores so what you really
正确的应用程序商店，所以你真的
have to be vigilant about as user is
必须 保持警惕，因为用户是
what those apps have access to in terms
这些应用程序可以访问哪些内容
of your own data is they could be
你自己的数据是他们可能的
something that you wouldn't actually
事实上你不会这样做
call malware but they would be doing
调用恶意软件，但他们会这样做
something that you would never think is
这是 你永远不会想到的
ok with your data so if you had for
确定你的数据，如果你有的话
example this is a very common example a
例如这是 一个 非常常见的例子a
business card scanner app that just
名片扫描仪应用程序，只是
uploaded a business card and turned it
上传了一张名片 并将其 打开
into a contact via what's called optical
通过所谓的光学接触到一个接触
character recognition sure you don't
字符识别确定你没有
have to enter it yourself and it has
必须自己输入，它已经
access to your contacts obviously
显然可以访问你的联系人
because it's uploading contacts very
因为它非常的上传联系人
often those those apps will just sell
通常那些应用程序只会销售
your information as well as the
您的信息还有
information of everybody who's in your
每个人在你的信息
contacts to marketing firms Wow and
联系营销公司哇和
that's the sort of thing that just is
这是诸如此类的事情， 仅仅是
endemic and is hard to identify
特有的，很难识别
hi and so really it's a matter of
嗨，真的这是一个问题
understanding what apps you've given
了解你提供的应用程序
what permissions to and trying to be
什么权限和试图成为什么
thoughtful about that the second thing
对第二件事深思熟虑
that is worth pointing out is Wi-Fi
值得指出的是Wi-Fi
alright so this is the same way that you
没问题，所以这和你一样
can connect to a malicious Wi-Fi network
可以连接到恶意的Wi-Fi网络
with a PC you can mitigate that risk
用PC可以减轻这种风险
slightly by using a VPN you can very
通过使用VPN你可以非常轻微
easily do that on a with a wireless
轻松地通过无线方式做到这一点
device as well or a cellular device and
设备以及蜂窝设备
those Wi-Fi networks that you often find
您经常发现的那些Wi-Fi网络
in airports that pop up free Wi-Fi for
在那些可以免费拨打Wi-Fi的机场
the show alphabetically towards the top
按字母顺序向顶部显示
of the list of SSIDs very very likely to
的SSID名单很有可能
be fraudulent and those very often doing
是欺诈性的，而且经常 在做
incall it in the middle attacks and
在中间攻击中加入
consent things like passwords if you
同意你的密码
have to enter them in a web browsing
必须在网页浏览中输入它们
sessions while you're connected to that
会议，而你连接到
road Wi-Fi there are a few apps in the
道路Wi-Fi有几个应用程序在
App Store that can actually help you
应用商店，可以真正帮助你
identify with Wi-Fi networks and those
识别Wi-Fi网络和那些
are very very good ideas from the
是非常非常好的想法
security best practices standpoint for
安全最佳实践的立场
everyone especially those of us who
每个人特别是我们这些谁
travel frequently so what you're saying
经常旅行，所以你在说什么
is when I see that open network that
是当我看到那个开放的网络
says FBI surveillance van I should you
FBI监控车说我应该
know it raises so many there's so many
知道它会产生如此之多的这么多
frightening concerns and you know you
可怕的担忧，你知道你
were in this world where I look for open
在这个我渴望开放的世界里
Wi-Fi and I want to use it and I save on
Wi-Fi，我想使用 它 ，我节省了
my data plan because it's free and
我的数据计划，因为它是免费的
available to me so maybe we just gotta
提供给我，所以也许我们必须得到
watch for for ones that we know and
注意我们所知道的 和
trust we're speaking with ryan from
我们正在和瑞安交谈
proof point he is the SVP of
他是SVP的证明点
cybersecurity strategy Ryan where can we
网络安全战略瑞安我们在哪里
get more information resources to help
获得更多的信息资源来帮助
us stay safe on our mobile devices so at
我们在我们的移动设备上保持安全
Birth wacom we focus on mobile quite
我们专注于手机的诞生wacom
heavily in our threat research you can
可以在我们的威胁研究中大量使用
find that at what we call our threatened
发现我们称之为受到威胁的东西
site blog and we wrote about the Pokemon
现场博客，我们写了 关于口袋妖怪
go malware we wrote about what we're
去我们写的关于 我们的恶意软件
seeing as a broader trend in q3 in that
在第三季度看到这是一个更广泛的趋势
quarterly chart report you mentioned
你提到的季度图表报告
earlier and we also have quite a lot of
早些时候，我们也有很多
best practices for everyone when they
每个人的最佳做法，当他们
use mobile devices that are all of their
使用他们所有的移动设备
own proof Wacom
自己的证明Wacom
very good Ryan thank you so much for
很好，瑞恩非常感谢你
your time tonight all the best and great
你今晚的时间一切顺利
speaking with you it was a pleasure care
跟你说话是一种快乐的关怀
cheers
干杯
you
您